http://www.cineworld.co.uk/terms/privacy-policy-and-cookies

Home
Terms, privacy & legal
Privacy Policy and Cookies
Terms, privacy & legal
Here are the Cineworld terms and conditions, privacy information and legal notices for all the services we provide. They are subject to change and can be updated on a regular basis.
Gift cards and e-Gift cards
Gift cards, e-Gift cards and gift box terms of use and cancellation rights
Offers and promotions
Competitions, prize draws and offers terms and conditions
In-cinema
Terms of entry, safety and security
Online, Phone and My Cineworld
Privacy Policy and Cookies
Unlimited card
Unlimited membership terms, cancellation and Unlimited member offers
1. Privacy Policy (Section 1)
2. Who are we and what do we do? (Section 2)
3. How to contact us? (Section 3)
4. What personal information do we collect and how do we use it? (Section 4)
5. Fulfilment of products and services (Section 4.1)
6. Verify the age of persons using our products and services (Section 4.2)
7. Providing and administering My Cineworld accounts (Section 4.3)
8. Providing our Unlimited membership scheme (Section 4.4)
9. Customer Services (Section 4.5)
10. Competitions, prize draws and other events and promotions (Section 4.6)
11. Your feedback about our products and services (Section 4.7)
12. Customer insight and analysis (Section 4.8)
13. Marketing communications (Section 4.9)
14. Business administration and legal compliance (Section 4.10)
15. Coronavirus (COVID-19) Contact Tracing (Section 4.11)
16. Health and Safety (Section 4.12)
17. How do we obtain your consent? (Section 5)
18. Our use of cookies and similar technologies (Section 6)
19. Who do we share your personal information with? (Section 7)
20. Transfers of your personal information overseas (Section 8)
21. Third party links and services (Section 9)
22. How long do we keep your personal information for? (Section 10)
23. Confidentiality and security of your personal information (Section 11)
24. How to access your information and your other rights (Section 12)
25. Changes to this privacy policy (Section 13)
26. Cookie policy
1. Privacy Policy (Section 1)
CINEWORLD CINEMAS
PRIVACY POLICY
IMPORTANT, PLEASE READ – CORONAVIRUS CONTACT TRACING: CINEWORLD IS COMMITTED TO ENSURING THE SAFETY OF ITS CUSTOMERS DURING THE ONGOING CORONAVIRUS (COVID-19) PANDEMIC. CINEWORLD PARTICIPATES IN CONTACT TRACING SCHEMES OPERATED BY YOUR LOCAL HEALH AUTHORITY. TO FIND OUT MORE PLEASE SEE SECTION 4.11 OF THIS PRIVACY NOTICE
Last updated September 2020
We respect the privacy of every person who visits or registers with www.cineworld.com, www.cineworld.co.uk, www.cineworld.ie and www.unlimitedcineworld.com or uses the Cineworld mobile applications for iPhone and Android (the “Sites”) and who uses the services that we make available from the Sites, on our telephone booking line, in our cinemas or through our customer services facilities (our “Services”) and we are committed to ensuring a safe online experience.
1 PURPOSE OF THIS POLICY
This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) explains our approach to any personal information that we might collect from you or which we have obtained about you from a third party, including someone who has purchased a gift for you, and the purposes for and the basis on which we process your personal information. This Privacy Policy also sets out your rights in respect of our processing of your personal information.
This Privacy Policy will inform you of the nature of the personal information about you that is processed by us and how you can request that we delete, update, transfer it and/or provide you with access to it.
This Privacy Policy is intended to assist you in making informed decisions when using the Sites and our Services. Please take a moment to read and understand it. Please note that it should be read in conjunction with our Online, Phone and My Cineworld Terms of Use (which includes our Website Terms of Use) and (where applicable) the Unlimited Card terms and conditions. These can be found by clicking here.
Please also note that this Privacy Policy only applies to the use of your personal information obtained by us, it does not apply to your personal information collected during your communications with third parties.
This Privacy Policy may vary from time to time so please check it regularly. Please see Changes to this Privacy Policy below for further details.
Back to top
2. Who are we and what do we do? (Section 2)
The Sites and our Services are operated by Cineworld Cinemas (“we”, “us” or “our”).
Cineworld Cinemas is made up of two companies, Cineworld Cinemas Limited and Adelphi-Carlton Limited, which are part of the same group and trade under the Cineworld brand to operate Cineworld Cinemas, the Sites and to provide the Services.
Cineworld Cinemas Limited is the data controller responsible for your personal information obtained in connection with the provision of our Sites and Services in the United Kingdom. Adelphi-Carlton Limited is the data controller responsible for your personal information obtained in connection with the provision of our Sites and Services in the Republic of Ireland.
Cineworld Cinemas Limited is an English company with registered company number: 01915767 and whose registered office is at 8th Floor Vantage London, Great West Road, Brentford, TW8 9AG, United Kingdom. Adelphi-Carlton Limited (trading as Cineworld Cinemas), is an Irish company with registered company number 7640 and whose registered office is at 8th Floor, Block E, Iveagh Court, Harcourt Road, Dublin 2, Republic of Ireland.
Back to top
3. How to contact us? (Section 3)
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or want to exercise your rights set out in this Privacy Policy, please contact us by:
sending an e-mail to: [email protected]; or
calling us on: 0333 003 3444 (UK) or 0818 304 204 (ROI)
post at: Cineworld Customer Services Department, Cineworld Cinemas, 8th Floor, Vantage London, Great West Road, Brentford TW8 9AG
Back to top
4. What personal information do we collect and how do we use it? (Section 4)
We obtain your personal information from the following sources:
Directly from you, either in person (at our cinemas or otherwise), via our Sites, on our social media pages or when you contact us or someone contacts us on your behalf;
Automated technologies, such as CCTV or other recording systems, cookies, server logs and other similar technologies;
From our group companies and third party service providers in the course of providing their services to us in connection with your use of our Sites and Services. Please see section 7 ‘Who do we share your personal information with?' to find out more about these group companies and third party service providers;
Providers of social media platforms (such as FaceBook, Twitter and Instagram) where you share our content through social media, by liking us on Facebook, following or tweeting about us on Twitter; and
Otherwise as explained below in this What Personal Information do we collect and how do we use it? section.
Our primary goal in collecting personal information about you is to: (i) verify your identity and age; (ii) provide our Services to you and carry out requests made by you on the Sites or in our cinemas; (iii) help us improve our products and services and develop and market new products and services; (iv) investigate or settle inquiries or disputes; (v) comply with any applicable law, court order, other judicial process, or the requirements of a regulator; (vi) enforce our agreements with you; (vii) protect the rights, property or safety of us or third parties, including our other customers and users of the Sites and at our cinemas; (viii) provide support for the provision of our Services; and (ix) use as otherwise required or permitted by law.
In particular, we use your personal information for the following purposes:
Back to top
5. Fulfilment of products and services (Section 4.1)
We collect and maintain personal information that is voluntarily submitted to us during the use of the Sites and/or our Services. We use the contact and payment details which are provided to us so that we can fulfil the supply of products and services which have been ordered from our Sites or in our cinemas. We will use contact information to send you service related communications relating to these orders. This includes your purchase of products and services, your registration for an account with us, your attendance at events hosted by us or our third party partners, your hire of our cinemas for your own events and the processing of returns and refunds. For example:
Ticket bookings, gifts and other online purchases.
If you wish to book tickets through our Sites we will need to know your name, and your email address. We may also need this information when you make any other purchases via our Sites, such as ordering food, drink, or 3D glasses. If you request a booking confirmation to be sent by SMS, we will also ask you to provide your mobile phone number.
If you wish to purchase a gift from the Gifts section of our Sites we will need to know your name, and email address. We will also need to know the name of the recipient and the delivery address for gifts sent by post or the name and email address of the recipient where gifts are sent by email.
We use this Information to process and fulfil your orders and to send you service related emails (and where requested, text messages) for your booking or purchase. We may also use these details to send you a follow-up service email after your cinema visit, to check that you were satisfied with our service.
If you choose to pay for your purchases on our websites by credit, debit or charge card those payments will be processed by our payment provider rather than by us. If you use a Cineworld gift card, e-gift code or other promotional code to pay for your purchases those payments may be processed by our gifts and promotions service providers rather than by us.
We may also receive part of the payment details such as your name, email address and some of the digits of your payment card number from our payment processor. These will be used to help connect your payment with your booking on our Site and may also be used by us if we provide you with a refund.
What is our legal basis?
It is necessary for us to use your personal information to perform our obligations in accordance with any contract that we may have with you such as your contract with us for your ticket or gift purchase. It is in our legitimate interest to use personal data of a gift recipient in order to provide them with the gifts purchased for them.
Back to top
6. Verify the age of persons using our products and services (Section 4.2)
We welcome children and young people to our cinemas. However, some of our Services and features available on our Sites (including online ticket booking, Unlimited memberships and My Cineworld accounts) have age restrictions attached to their use. These age restrictions are explained in the terms and conditions relating to our Services, which are located here.
This means that we may need to ask you to provide your date of birth and, where our products or services are being purchased as a gift, the date of birth of the recipient of the gift.
We may also use your date of birth to understand more about our customers (see the Customer Insight and Analysis section for more details about our use of your personal information for this purpose).
What is our legal basis?
Where we use your personal information to verify you or the person receiving our Services meets any age restrictions which we have set, it is in our legitimate interests to do so. Where we use your date of birth to prevent you from accessing age restricted films, we do so because this is necessary for us to comply with legal obligations to which we are subject. When you use our Services, it is also necessary for us to process your personal information for the purpose of performing our contract with you.
Back to top
7. Providing and administering My Cineworld accounts (Section 4.3)
If you register for a My Cineworld account or any other accounts on our sites, we will ask you to provide your name, e-mail address, postcode and your favourite or local cinema. We will also ask you to provide a password for your My Cineworld account. Alternatively, you may be able to register for, or log in to, your My Cineworld account using your Facebook, Google or Twitter profile and we will use your personal information from your profile to create, or log you in to, your My Cineworld account. You can also voluntarily provide us with additional information when using your My Cineworld account, for example your postal address and phone numbers. You can update and amend the contact details and some other personal information we hold about you at any time through your My Cineworld account.
We will use this personal information to provide you with the online functions available within the My Cineworld account and apps, including facilitating your purchase of our products and services via your My Cineworld account and/or the apps. This personal information is also used to identify you when you visit and interact with other areas of our Sites (see the Customer Insight and Analysis section for more details about our use of your personal information for this purpose).
You can also ask for your payment card details to be securely stored by our payment services providers, who process payments and store all credit and debit card details on our behalf, to help speed up the online booking process for you.
What is our legal basis?
It is necessary for us to use your personal information to perform our obligations in accordance with any contract that we may have with you such as your contract with us for your use of a My Cineworld account.
Back to top
8. Providing our Unlimited membership scheme (Section 4.4)
If you purchase an Unlimited membership for yourself or as a gift for another person, we will collect and use personal information about you and, if applicable, the gift recipient, in accordance with the purposes described in Sections 4.1 to 4.3 of this Privacy Policy. In addition, we will also ask you to provide your postal address and telephone numbers (or those of the gift recipient), so we know where to send the Unlimited card and how to get in touch if we need to speak with you (or the gift recipient) about the Unlimited membership account. You will also need to provide us with a photo of yourself or, if applicable, the gift recipient, which will be printed on the Unlimited card and used to verify the identity of the person who uses the Unlimited card and for fraud prevention purposes. If you choose to pay the Unlimited membership subscription fee by monthly direct debit we will need your bank details, in addition to your payment card details, to set up your direct debit and take payment from you.
Where you use your Unlimited card to obtain discounts or benefits from our third party partners, we may receive personal information about your use of your Unlimited card from these third party partners. Our third party partners are identified on our Sites here. Please see the Customer Insight and Analysis section for more details about how we use the personal information that we receive from our third party partners.
If you purchase an Unlimited membership for someone else as a gift, we will still need some details about you (so we can contact you about your gift and you can pay) but we will also ask for the details of the person who will be the Unlimited member. Where you submit personal information about that person to us, you confirm that you have all necessary permissions and consents to do so (including the consent of the Unlimited member’s parent or guardian, if they are under 18). We will also let the Unlimited member know that you have bought them Unlimited membership as a gift and provided us with personal information about them.
To book tickets in advance using your Unlimited Card and to manage your Unlimited membership online (including your email and text marketing preferences and online unsubscribe functions), you will need to set up a My Cineworld account (if you haven’t already got one) and link it with your Unlimited membership account. Please see the ‘Providing and administering My Cineworld accounts’ section for further details.
As a part of your Unlimited membership, we will use your contact details to send you service communications, including information about your membership such as renewal reminders, account information and membership summaries and sometimes details of new cinema openings or changes or additions to our selection of Unlimited partners, the latest films as well as hints and tips on how to make the most of your membership (for example a series of messages about how and where to use your Unlimited Card when you first join Unlimited). You can find out more about what’s included with the Unlimited membership service here. In addition, where we have a lawful right to send you marketing communications, we will also send you marketing relating to your Unlimited membership. Please see the Marketing communications section for further information.
What is our legal basis?
Where you have purchased an Unlimited membership for yourself or as a gift for someone else, it is necessary for us to use your personal information to perform our obligations in accordance with any contract that we may have with you such as your contract with us for your purchase or use of Unlimited membership. It is in our legitimate interest to use your photograph for identification purposes, to help ensure the Unlimited scheme is used fairly and for fraud detection and prevention purposes.
Where an Unlimited membership has been purchased as a gift, it is in our legitimate interest to use personal data of a gift recipient in order to provide them with the gift which has been purchased for them.
Back to top
9. Customer Services (Section 4.5)
Our Sites and our cinemas use various user interfaces to allow you to request information about our products and services: these include printed and electronic enquiry forms, dedicated email addresses, our social media pages and a telephone enquiry service. Contact information may be requested in each case, together with details of other personal information that is relevant to your customer service enquiry. This information is used in order to enable us to respond to your requests.
What is our legal basis?
It is in our legitimate interest to use your personal information in such a way to ensure that we provide the very best customer service we can to you.
Back to top
10. Competitions, prize draws and other events and promotions (Section 4.6)
From time to time, we may run prize draws, prize competitions and other promotions on our Sites, on our social media accounts and/or in our cinemas. We may also run events at other locations. For the purposes of administering such promotions and events, we may process your name, contact details (including email address, postal address and/or telephone number), social media handle (if relevant) and any other personal information volunteered by you in your promotion entry. For certain competitions and events, we may process and publicise images, videos or sound recordings that you volunteer to us.
What is our legal basis?
It is necessary for us to use your personal information to perform our obligations in accordance with any contract that we may have with you (e.g. the terms and conditions applicable to the promotion) or it is in our legitimate interest to use your personal information to enable you to participate in any prize draws, prize competitions and other promotions. We will only use photographs we take of you at events where we have your consent to do so.
Back to top
11. Your feedback about our products and services (Section 4.7)
From time to time we will contact you to invite you to provide feedback about our products and services in the form of online or in-cinema surveys. We use this information to help us improve the quality of service provided by our staff and in our cinemas. We also use your feedback to monitor the quality of our products and services and to assist with the selection of future product and service lines.
What is our legal basis?
It is in our legitimate business interests to use the information you provide to us in your feedback for the purposes described above.
Back to top
12. Customer insight and analysis (Section 4.8)
We analyse your contact details and other information provided by you during your use of the Sites and our Services, including your date of birth, with other personal information that we collect or observe about you from your interactions with our Sites, our email communications to you and/or with our products and services in our cinemas, such as the products and services you have purchased or viewed.
If you are an Unlimited member, we may also receive information from third party partners about your use of your Unlimited card when purchasing or using our third party partner’s products or services.
Where you have given your consent (where lawfully required), we use cookies, log files and other technologies to collect personal information from the computer hardware and software you use to access the Sites, or from your mobile. This includes the following:
an IP address to monitor Sites traffic and volume;
a session ID to track usage statistics on our Sites;
information regarding your personal or professional interests, demographics, buying habits, experiences with our products and contact preferences.
Our web pages, mobile applications and e-mails contain “cookies” "web beacons" or “pixel tags.” (“Tags”). Tags allow us to track receipt of an e-mail to you, to count users that have visited a web page, analyse how a user has interacted with our content or third party content or opened an e-mail and collect other types of aggregate information. Once you click on an e-mail that contains a Tag, your contact information may subsequently be cross-referenced to the source e-mail and the relevant Tag.
In some of our e-mail messages, we use a “click-through URL” linked to certain websites administered by us or on our behalf. We may track click-through data to assist in determining interest in particular topics and measure the effectiveness of these communications. Please see our Cookie policy for further information.
This information is used to create profiles and insights about your cinema habits and the cinema habits of our other customers and helps us to get to know our customers better. Where we have your consent to do so, we will also use your location data for customer insight purposes. To the extent this information is collected by Tags set by third party partners this information will be shared with the relevant third party for its own analysis and advertising purposes.  Please see our Cookie policy for further information about our third party partners and how they might use your information.
By using this information, we are able to measure the effectiveness of our content and how visitors use our Sites and our Services. This allows us to learn which pages of our Sites are most attractive to our visitors, which parts of our Sites are the most interesting, how customers use our Services and what kind of offers our registered users like to see.
We also use this information to help us with the selection of future product and service lines, cinema, website and app design and development, to identify appropriate partners whose offers we might obtain for you as a Cineworld customer and to remember your customer preferences.
We also use this information for marketing purposes (see the Marketing communications section below for further details).
What is our legal basis?
Where your personal information is completely anonymised, we do not require a legal basis to use it as the information will no longer constitute personal information that is regulated under data protection laws. However, our collection and use of such anonymised personal information may be subject to other laws where your consent is required. Please see our Cookie policy for further details.
Where your personal information is not in an anonymous form, it is in our legitimate interest to use your personal information in such a way to ensure that we provide the very best products and services to you and our other customers.
We will only use your location data for customer insight purposes where we have your consent to do so.
Back to top
13. Marketing communications (Section 4.9)
We carry out the following marketing activities using your personal information:
Email and text marketing. We use information that we observe about you from your interactions with our Sites, our email communications to you and/or with our products and services in our cinemas (see the Customer Insight and Analysis section above for more details of the information collected and how it is collected) and/or your email address and mobile phone number to send you marketing communications by email and text message, where you have consented to receive such marketing communications, or where we have another lawful basis to do so.
What is our legal basis?
Where your personal information is not in an anonymous form, it is in our legitimate interest to use your personal information for marketing purposes. We will only send you marketing communications via email and text message where you have consented to receive such marketing communications, or where we have a lawful right to do so.
Online personalised advertising. We use information that we observe about you from your interactions with our Sites, our email communications to you and/or with our products and services in our cinemas (see the Customer Insight and Analysis section above for more details of the information collected and how it is collected) to provide you with personalised online advertising.
What is our legal basis?
Where your personal information is not in an anonymous form, it is in our legitimate interest to use your personal information for marketing purposes.
Social media remarketing. We use information that we observe about you from your interactions with our Sites, our email communications to you and/or with our products and services in our cinemas (see the Customer Insight and Analysis section above for more details of the information collected and how it is collected) to provide you with personalised advertising on social media channels operated by Facebook and/or Google where you are a registered user of such services.
We do this using Facebook Customer Audiences and/or Google Customer Match respectively. Please note that such activity requires that we share your encrypted email address with Facebook and/or Google and is also subject to the privacy choices you have elected to make on such services.
What is our legal basis?
Where your personal information is not in an anonymous form, it is in our legitimate interest to use your personal information for marketing purposes.
Social media insight. Where you are a registered user of Facebook, or of a Google service, we will use your email address in an encrypted format to enable Facebook and Google to find other registered users of their services that share similar interests to you based on:
- information that we observe about you from your interactions with our Sites, our email communications to you and/or with our products and services in our cinemas (see the Customer Insight and Analysis section above for more details of the information collected and how it is collected); and
- the information Facebook and/or Google hold about you.
We do this using Facebook Lookalike Audiences and/or Google Similar Audience respectively. Please note that such activity is subject to the privacy choices you have elected to make on such services.
What is our legal basis?
Where your personal information is not in an anonymous form, it is in our legitimate interest to use your personal information for marketing purposes.
Use of Anonymised Personal Information.  Where your personal information is completely anonymised, we do not require a legal basis to use it as the personal information will no longer constitute personal information that is regulated under data protection laws. However, our collection and use of such anonymised personal information may be subject to other laws where your consent is required. Please see our Cookie policy for further details.
Back to top
14. Business administration and legal compliance (Section 4.10)
We use your personal information for the following business administration and legal compliance purposes:
to comply with our legal obligations;
to protect our business and your accounts from fraud and other illegal activities
to enforce our legal rights;
protect rights of third parties; and
in connection with a business transition such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of our assets.
What is our legal basis?
Where we use your personal information in connection with a business transition, enforce our legal rights, or to protect the rights of third parties it is in our legitimate interest to do so. For all other purposes described in this section, it is our legal obligation to use your personal information to comply with any legal obligations imposed upon us such as a court order.
Back to top
15. Coronavirus (COVID-19) Contact Tracing (Section 4.11)
We participate in government Coronavirus (COVID-19) contact tracing schemes operated by public health authorities. When you make your booking (online or in-cinema), we will request certain contact details and we may share this information, together with details of the data and time of your visit to our Cinema, with public health authorities if it is requested (because the public health authority is concerned about a local outbreak).
If we are informed of an outbreak, we will not contact you. Instead, you will be contacted by the relevant public health authority that has requested our customers’ details.
If you are contacted by a public health authority / contact tracing scheme, and you are asked to provide any personal information, you should ensure that the caller is genuine. You should be cautious that fraudsters or scammers could seek to obtain information from you by pretending to be a contact tracing agency. Please see government and/or your local health authority’s guidance for more information about contact tracing.
We will only retain the data that we collect for this purpose in line with government guidance (typically for a period of no more than 21 days). Please see the How long do we keep your personal information for? section for further information.
What is our legal basis?
It is in our and our customers’ legitimate interests to contribute to the public health efforts to tackle COVID-19. In some areas or countries, we may also be under a legal obligation to collect your contact details.
You can object to our use of your personal information for this purpose by contacting us by
email ([email protected]) or telephone (0333 003 3444), but we may not give effect to your request if we have decided that the use of your personal information for this purpose is mandatory as a result of measures and/or guidance applicable to your area or country. You can also exercise your rights (including your right of objection) in respect of this activity as set out in the How to access your information and your other rights section.
Back to top
16. Health and Safety (Section 4.12)
We may use your personal information to help ensure we provide a safe and secure environment for our customers, staff and others when visiting our cinemas.  This may include using personal information which is gathered for health and safety purposes, including any accident report or claim log (including CCTV images) in respect of an accident or incident which occurs in one of our cinemas.
As this may include information relating to your health, it could fall within special categories of data which is defined under relevant data protection legislation as including personal informaton revealing racial or ethnic origin, religious beliefs and information concerning health (as well as various others).
We may also use this information to establish, exercise or defend any legal claim in relation to the accident or incident, including sharing this information with our insurance providers.
What is our legal basis?
Where we use your personal information in connection with an accident or incident as described above it is in our legitimate interest to do so and, in some cases, we may also need to process it to comply with our legal obligations, including health and safety related obligations.
Where we process personal information relating to your health for this purpose, we may process this information to exercise rights in relation to a legal claim (for example, a claim relating to an accident or incident).
We may also process information relating to your health if it is in the substantial public interest that we do so and/or if it is necessary for the purposes of carrying out our obligations and exercising specific rights relating to relevant social protection law (for example to ensure that we satisfy our obligations at law to provide equality of opportunity or treatment to people with different states of physical or mental health, or to ensure that our services are provided in accordance with health and safety and/or occupier’s liability legislation).
Back to top
17. How do we obtain your consent? (Section 5)
Where our use of your personal information requires your consent, you can provide such consent:
at the time we collect your personal information following the instructions provided; or
by informing us by e-mail, post or phone using the contact details set out in this Privacy Policy.
The legal basis of consent is only used by us in relation to processing that is entirely voluntary – it is not used for processing that is necessary or obligatory in any way.
You may at any time withdraw the specific consent you give to our processing your personal data. Please see How to access your information and your other rights section below for more details. Please note even if you withdraw consent for us to use your personal data for a particular purpose we may continue to process your personal data for other purposes where we have a legal right to do so.
Back to top
18. Our use of cookies and similar technologies (Section 6)
Our Sites use certain cookies, pixels, beacons, log files and other technologies of which you should be aware. Please see our Cookie policy to find out more about the cookies we use and how to manage and delete cookies.
Back to top
19. Who do we share your personal information with? (Section 7)
We may share your personal information for the purposes described in section 4 of this Privacy Policy:
internally with other companies in our group (which means our subsidiaries and our ultimate holding company (Cineworld Group plc) and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006); and
externally with third party service providers.
The categories of third party service providers that we share your personal information with are:
providers of ticketing systems;
suppliers of systems and services that help us provide and administer our gift products;
scheme administrators who help us operate our Unlimited scheme;
payment processors;
delivery companies;
providers of customer service and call centre functions;
suppliers who host, provide, manage, support or administer certain aspects of our websites, phone booking service, IT systems and data centres;
providers of customer surveys and customer insight analytics;
suppliers of email, online and social media advertising and other marketing systems and services such as Salesforce;
third parties who help us to run or administer competitions or deliver prizes;
third parties who host our events;
with our professional advisers such as our lawyers, accountants, health and safety consultants and insurance brokers for our business administration and legal purposes;
debt collection agencies and others for the purposes of enforcing any agreements that we have with you;
Social media sites and platforms such as Facebook for marketing purposes (although we will only share your email address in encrypted form – for further information please see the Marketing Communications section above)
third party advertising partners for targeted advertising purposes – for further information please see the above “Customer insight and analysis” section (section 4.8) and “Our Use of Cookies and Similar Technologies” section (section 6);
any other third party where we are obliged to, or permitted to do so, by law, court order or to comply with any search warrant or similar instrument presented to us by any law enforcement, government officer or regulatory authority;
in the event that our business is sold or integrated with another business, our lawyers, and other professional advisers, any prospective purchasers' lawyers and professional advisers, and any prospective purchaser (subject to duties of confidentiality).
Back to top
20. Transfers of your personal information overseas (Section 8)
8.1 Internally within our group
We transfer your personal information within our group as described in section 7.
The use of your personal information is governed by an intra-group agreement and although we do not routinely transfer your personal data from the EEA to a non-EEA jurisdiction if we do so in the future we will ensure that there is a lawful basis for transferring personal information outside the EEA, this may include use of EU ‘model clauses’ which have been approved by the European Commission.
8.2 To external third parties
Some of the third parties that we describe in section 7 may be located outside of the EEA or may otherwise transfer your personal data outside of the EEA.
Where we transfer your personal data to external third parties, we take appropriate steps to ensure that your personal information is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and all applicable laws.
In respect of transfers of your personal information outside of the EEA, this means that we will ensure that there is a lawful basis for transferring personal information outside the EEA. Our standard practice is to use ‘model clauses’ which have been approved by the European Commission for such transfers. We may also rely on other mechanisms where appropriate, including reliance on a third party’s ‘binding corporate rules’ or ‘EU-US Privacy Shield’ certification.
Back to top
21. Third party links and services (Section 9)
Our Sites contain links to third party websites and services, including those of our third party partners. Please remember that when you use a link to go from our Sites to another website or you request a service from a third party, this Privacy Policy no longer applies.
Your browsing and interaction on any other websites, or your dealings with any other third party service provider, is subject to that website’s or third party service provider’s own rules and policies.
We do not monitor, control, or endorse the privacy practices of any third parties.
We encourage you to become familiar with the privacy practices of every website you visit or third party service provider that you deal with and to contact them if you have any questions about their respective privacy policies and practices.
This Privacy Policy applies solely to personal information collected by us through our Sites and Services and does not apply to these third party websites and third party service providers.
Back to top
22. How long do we keep your personal information for? (Section 10)
Whenever we collect or process your personal data we will usually keep it for one year after our last interaction with you or otherwise in accordance with our data retention policy, pursuant to which we do not retain personal data for longer than is necessary for the purposes for which it is collected. We will keep personal data you give us in relation to any contract that we have with you for seven years. If your information is only useful for a short period e.g. for specific marketing campaigns we may delete it.
If your information is only useful for a short period e.g. for specific marketing campaigns or for coronavirus (Covid-19) contact tracing, we may delete it after a shorter period (e.g. 21 days for contact tracing). At the end of that retention period, your data will either be deleted or anonymised, for example by aggregation with other data so that it can be used in a non-identifiable way for statistical analysis and business planning. We keep the length of time that we hold your personal data for under review.
Back to top
23. Confidentiality and security of your personal information (Section 11)
We are committed to keeping the personal information you provide to us secure and we will take reasonable precautions to protect your personal information from loss, misuse or alteration.
We have implemented information security policies, rules and technical measures to protect the personal information that we have under our control from:
unauthorised access;
improper use or disclosure;
unauthorised modification; and
unlawful destruction or accidental loss.
All of our employees and data processors (i.e. those who process your personal information on our behalf, for the purposes listed above), who have access to, and are associated with the processing of personal information, are obliged to respect the confidentiality of the personal information of all users of our Services.
Back to top
24. How to access your information and your other rights (Section 12)
You have the following rights in relation to the personal information we hold about you. You can exercise these rights by contacting us using the contact details set out in Section 3 of this Privacy Policy or using any other method described below:
Your right of access.
If you ask us, we’ll confirm whether we’re processing your personal information and, if so, provide you with a copy of that personal information (along with certain other details). If you require additional copies, we may need to charge a reasonable fee.
Your right to rectification.
If the personal information we hold about you is inaccurate or incomplete, you’re entitled to have it rectified. If we’ve shared your personal information with others, we’ll let them know about the rectification where possible. If you ask us, where possible and lawful to do so, we’ll also tell you who we’ve shared your personal information with so that you can contact them directly.
If you have a My Cineworld account, you can log in and amend your contact details and email and text marketing preferences whenever you like.
Your right to erasure.
You can ask us to delete or remove your personal information in some circumstances such as where we no longer need it or if you withdraw your consent (where applicable). If we’ve shared your personal information with others, we’ll let them know about the erasure where possible. If you ask us, where it is possible and lawful for us to do so, we’ll also tell you who we’ve shared your personal information with so that you can contact them directly.
Your right to restrict processing.
You can ask us to ‘block’ or suppress the processing of your personal information in certain circumstances such as where you contest the accuracy of that personal information or you object to us processing it. It won’t stop us from storing your personal information though. We’ll tell you before we lift any restriction. If we’ve shared your personal information with others, we’ll let them know about the restriction where it is possible for us to do so. If you ask us, where it is possible and lawful for us to do so, we’ll also tell you who we’ve shared your personal information with so that you can contact them directly.
Your right to data portability.
With effect from 25 May 2018, you have the right, in certain circumstances, to obtain personal information you’ve provided us with (in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format) and to reuse it elsewhere or to ask us to transfer this to a third party of your choice.
Your right to object.
You can ask us to stop processing your personal information, and we will do so, if we are:
- relying on our own or someone else’s legitimate interests to process your personal information, except if we can demonstrate compelling legal grounds for the processing; or
- processing your personal information for direct marketing.
You can ask us to stop sending you marketing communications sent to you by email or text at any time by using the ‘opt-out’ or ‘unsubscribe’ link that we will present to you in the marketing communication. Please note that it may take us a few days (but usually no longer than 14 days) to ensure our marketing systems are updated and during this period you may still receive marketing communications from us.
Your rights in relation to automated decision-making and profiling.
You have the right not to be subject to a decision when it’s based on automatic processing, including profiling, if it produces a legal effect or similarly significantly affects you, unless such profiling is necessary for entering into, or the performance of, a contract between you and us.
Your right to withdraw consent.
If we rely on your consent (or explicit consent) as our legal basis for processing your personal information, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time.
Your right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority.
If you have a concern about any aspect of our privacy practices, including the way we’ve handled your personal information, you can report it to relevant Supervisory Authority which, in relation to provision of our Sites and Services in:
the UK, the supervisory authority is the UK Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO). You can find details about how to do this on the ICO website at https://ico.org.uk/concerns/ or by calling their helpline on 0303 123 1113, and
the Republic of Ireland, the supervisory authority is the Data Protection Commission (DPC). You can find details about how to do this on the DPC website at https://dataprotection.ie/docs/Making-a-Complaint-to-the-Data-Protection-Commissioner/r/18.htm or emailing them at [email protected]
Back to top
25. Changes to this privacy policy (Section 13)
To ensure that you are always aware of how we use your personal information we will update this Privacy Policy from time to time to reflect any changes to our use of your personal information. We may also make changes as required to comply with changes in applicable law or regulatory requirements. We will post any changes on our Sites to keep you aware and if you are an Unlimited member or have a My Cineworld account we will notify you by e-mail of any significant changes. However, we encourage you to review this Privacy Policy periodically to be informed of how we use your personal information.
Back to top
26. Cookie policy
Cookie Policy
Last Updated 17 August 2020
This cookie policy (“Cookie Policy”) is intended to inform you how we use “cookies” and similar technologies on our websites at www.cineworld.co.uk, www.cineworld.ie, www.cineworld.com and www.unlimitedcineworld.com and in our mobile applications (“Sites”) and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our Sites. Please take a moment to read and understand this Cookie Policy. This Cookie Policy should also be read in conjunction with our Privacy Policy and our Online, Phone and My Cineworld Terms & Conditions (which contain our Website Terms of Use).
If you access our Sites from the UK or the Channel Islands, ‘we’ means Cineworld Cinemas Limited, if you access our Sites from the Republic of Ireland ‘we’ means Adelphi-Carlton Limited. We are part of the same group and trade under the Cineworld brand to operate Cineworld Cinemas and the Sites.  Please see our Privacy Policy to find out more about us.
WHAT ARE COOKIES?
Cookies and similar technologies are very small text documents or pieces of code, which often include an anonymous unique identifier. When you visit a website or use a mobile application, a computer asks your computer or mobile device for permission to store this file on your computer or mobile device and access information from it. Information gathered through cookies and similar technologies may include the date and time of visits and how you are using the particular website or mobile application. Cookies are used by us as part of our Sites and they are also used by some of our third party partners.
For more details on cookies and similar technologies please visit All About Cookies. For the purposes of the remaining sections of this Cookie Policy we will refer to all technologies using the above features as “cookies”.
CONSENT TO OUR USE OF COOKIES
By using any of the Sites you acknowledge that we may store and access essential cookies on your computer or other device. Necessary cookies are cookies which are essential for the operation of our Sites.
Further, where you give permission, we may also store and access certain non-essential cookies on your computer or other device. These cookies are not essential to the operation of our Sites but allow us to provide additional functionality or to gather additional information about your use of our Sites. You are not obliged to give consent to our use of non-essential cookies and we will not place such cookies until you have given your consent.
If you wish to block or delete cookies, or you would like to withdraw consent to our use of non-essential cookies, you can find out how to do so below.
WHAT DO WE DO WITH COOKIES?
Necessary Cookies
We use cookies where they are essential for the operation of the Sites, for example to remember that you are signed in to the Sites and to uniquely identify your browsing session on our Sites, which allows us to coordinate this information with data from our Sites server. Without these cookies, services that you have asked for, like booking tickets, cannot be provided.  Analytics Cookies
We use “analytics” cookies. These, along with other information, allow us to calculate the aggregate number of people using the Sites and which features of our Sites are most popular, whether you have visited before and the website that you visited prior to visiting our Sites. We use this information to improve the Sites. We do not generally store any information that you provide to us in an analytics cookie.
Display Adverts
We use these cookies to deliver adverts that are more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement on our Sites and help measure the effectiveness of the advertising campaign. They are usually placed by advertising networks with our permission. They remember that you have visited our Sites and this information is shared with other organisations such as advertisers so that they can make their advertising more relevant to you when you visit their websites (including social media sites).
Social Media Cookies
We use cookies to personalise your interaction with social media, such as Twitter, Facebook, and Google.  Such cookies recognise users of those social media sites when you view social media content on our Sites.  They also allow you to quickly share content across social media, through the use of simple ‘sharing’ buttons.
Our Sites also contains features that enable you to use your Facebook, Google and Twitter accounts to sign in and create/maintain an account with us and to enable us to store your content. This involves the use of cookies.
Targeting Cookies
We use targeting cookies help us to deliver our adverts including film adverts when you visit other websites, such as news websites. This is known as ‘retargeting’. This technique helps to ensure that the ads you receive are more relevant to you and your interests. These cookies help to measure the effectiveness of an ad (for example, by reporting whether you have clicked on it) and can also limit the number of times that you see an ad (for example, if you see it twice but don’t click on it, you may not see it again). These cookies are usually placed by advertising networks that we and other advertisers work with to deliver ads. They remember that you have visited a website and this information is shared with other ad networks to show you relevant ads.
MORE INFORMATION
The table below sets out more information about the individual cookies used in the Website and the purposes for which they are used:
Cookie Type
Name of Cookie
Purpose
Duration
Necessary
Necessary cookies are essential and help you navigate our Sites. These cookies maintain information based on your activity on our Sites, like searching for a cinema, selecting your language or making a booking via our Sites. This helps to support security and basic functionality of the Sites.
These cookies are necessary for the proper operation of our Sites.
CONSENTMGR
This cookie will be used to store the overall consent captured from the cookie settings tool.
1 year
__cfduid
The cookie is set by CloudFare. The cookie is used to identify individual clients behind a shared IP address and apply security settings on a per-client basis. It does not correspond to any user ID in the web application and does not store any personally identifiable information.
4 weeks
gdpr__status
Determines whether this visitor has accepted the cookie consent box. This ensures that the cookie consent box will not be presented again upon re-entry.
6 months
JSESSIONID
Preserves users states across page requests.
Session
webxx
Used by website load balancer to route web traffic.
Session
rc::c
Used to distinguish between users and bots.
Session
SERVERID
Used to assign the visitor a specific server – this function is necessary for the functionality of the website.
1 day
isLoggedIn
Stores a user's logged in status on the website.
Session
routes
The cookie tells the router which endpoint is handling the session, ensuring that client requests use the cookie so that they are routed to the same pod.
Session
lang
Remembers users selected language or the region that you are in.
1 day
Analytics
These cookies enable us to store information such as the time you visit our Sites, whether you have visited before and the website that you visited prior to visiting our Sites. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to our Sites, where our visitors to our Sites have come from and the pages they have visited.
Switching off these cookies will mean we can’t gather information to improve user experience.
For more information about Google Analytics please see: http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html
utag_main
The cookie is set by Tealium. The cookie is used to track the information about a user visit. The cookie is used to keep a record of a unique ID, the timestamp of when a user visit has started, the pages that have been viewed, and the number of the visits to the website. The data helps to improve the website and provide a better user-experience.
1 year
_utma
_utmb
_utmc
_utmz
_ga
_gat
_gid
gtag.js
These cookies are provided by Google Analytics and are used to track and collect information about how visitors use our website. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the website. The cookies collect information in a way that does not directly identify anyone, including the number of visitors to the website and blog, where visitors have come to the website from and the pages they visited.
The longest lasting cookie of this type last for up to 2 years from set/update.
collect
Used to send data to Google Analytics about the visitors device and behaviour.  Tracks visitors across devices and marketing channels.
Session
IDSYNC
This cookie is used for advertising purposes.
1 year
Display Adverts
We use these cookies to deliver adverts that are more relevant to you and your interests. If you switch off these cookies, adverts will still be displayed but they won’t be tailored to your interests.
This information may also be shared by our agency with other organisations such as advertisers so that they can make their advertising more relevant to you when you visit their websites (including social media sites).
_dlt
This is a Doubeclick cookie that is used to track user behaviour to deliver advertisements that are relevant to a user.
Session
_gcl_au
This cookie is used by Google Analytics to understand user interaction with the website.
3 months
_schn
Tracks individual sessions allowing the website to compile statistical data from multiple visits.  Data can be used to create leads for marketing purposes.
Session
_scid
Sets a unique ID for the visitor that allows third party advertisers to target the visitor with relevant advertisement. Service is provided by third party advertisement hubs which facilitates real time bidding for advertisers.
13 months
ads/ga-audiences
Used by Google AdsWords to re-engage visitors that are likely to convert to customers based on the visitor’s online behaviour across websites.
Session
APID
This cookie is used to store information of how a user behaves on multiple websites. This information is them used to customize the relevant ads to be displayed to the users.
1 year
APIDTS
Collects data on visitors’ preferences and behaviour on the website.  This information is used to make content and advertisements more relevant to the specific visitor.
1 day
audience
Used to determine whether the video-ads have been displayed correctly on the website are not shown the same ads more times than intended.
1 year
B
Collects anonymous data related to the user’s website visits, such as number of visits, average time spent on website and which pages have been loaded. Registered data is used to categorise the user’s interest and demographic profiles with the purpose of customising the website content depending on the visitor.
1 year
IDE
Used by Google DoubleClick and stores information about how the user uses the website and any other advertisement before visiting the website. This is used to present users with ads that are relevant to them according to the user profile.
1 year
_msuuid_
This cookie is used by Marin Software and is used to store unique user ID for the users for tracking and targeted advertisement purposes.
1 year
sc_at
Used by Snapchat to implement advertisement content on the website. The cookie detects the efficiency of the ads and collects visitor data for further visitor segmentation.
1 year
Social Media
Cineworld, selected 3rd parties and social media companies use these cookies to run, track and analyse our advertising on social media websites.
This allows a user to easily comment or share an article with their peers through the social network.
If you switch off these cookies, adverts will still be displayed but they won’t be tailored to your interests.
Social    fr
The cookie is set by Facebook to show relevant advertisements to the users and measure and improve the advertisements. The cookie also tracks the behaviour of the user across the web on sites that have Facebook pixel or Facebook social plugin.
2 months
_fbp
This cookie is set by Facebook to deliver advertisements to users when they are on Facebook or a digital platform powered by Facebook advertising after visiting this website.
3 months
tr
The cookie is set by Facebook to deliver a series of advertisement products such as real time bidding from third party advertisers.
Session
Targeting
These targeting and advertising cookies, are set through our site by our advertising partners, including Warner Bros, and our agency Spark Foundry.
They are specifically designed to gather information from you on your device to display advertisements to you based on relevant topics that interest you.
If you switch off these cookies, adverts may still be displayed but they won’t be tailored to your interests.
For more information about how your data is used by our advertising partners and agency, please visit the following:
Spark Foundry Privacy Policy
Warner Bros Privacy Policy
Floodlight
Floodlight cookies enable us to understand if you complete certain actions on our website(s) after you have seen or clicked through one of our display/ video advertisements served on Google or other platforms via DoubleClick. DoubleClick uses this cookie to understand the content with which you have engaged on our website(s) so they may subsequently deliver some targeted advertisements to you.
These cookies last the duration of a campaign
Facebook Pixel
The Facebook pixel is an analytics tool that allows us to measure the effectiveness of our advertising by understanding the actions users take on your website. It ensures that our advertisements are shown to the right people.
These cookies last the duration of a campaign
Snap Pixel
The Snap Pixel is a piece of JavaScript code that helps Advertisers measure the cross-device impact of Campaigns. Advertisers will be able to see how many Snapchatters take action on their website(s) after seeing their Ad.
These cookies last the duration of a campaign
Amazon Pixel
Amazon remarketing and conversion pixels help advertisers better reach their intended audience and measure the success of their advertising campaigns that are run through Amazon.
These pixels show interest-based ads to you across the Internet.
These cookies last the duration of a campaign
Pinterest Tag
The Pinterest Tag allows us to measure how effectively our ads send traffic to oour website. It helps us to identify people who have visited a specific page or taken a desired action on oour website.
These cookies last the duration of a campaign
WHAT HAPPENS WHEN YOU REFUSE, BLOCK OR DELETE COOKIES?
In order to use some parts of our Sites you will need to accept cookies. If you choose to withhold consent to our use of cookies, or you subsequently block or delete cookies, some aspects of our Sites may not work properly and you may not be able to access all or part of our Sites.
HOW TO MANAGE OR BLOCK COOKIES
In relation to the non-essential cookies that are used by the Sites, you can manage your cookie preferences by clicking
here.
You can also block the use of cookies altogether by activating the relevant settings in your browser. For more information on cookie management and blocking or deleting cookies for a wide variety of browsers, visit All About Cookies.
Last update: 17 August 2020
Back to top
Experiences
Offers & Competitions
Snacks & drinks
Movie seasons
Venue Hire and Events
Toggle navigation
